Finding Aid for C. Loring Brace papers, 1954-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
C. Loring Brace papers
1954-2009
1971-2008
Brace, C. Loring.
2013095 Aa 2
C. Loring Brace, professor of Anthropology at the University of Michigan and Curator of Biological Anthropology at the University's Museum of Anthropology. Known for extensive field research on cranial and dental material of hominid remains all over the world, particularly in Asia, to study human evolution. He has done considerable research on how structural reduction can result from Probable Mutation Effect, as well as on the development and application of the 'race' concept.
39 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were received in 2012 (donor no. 10509 ).
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The C. Loring Brace papers records are open for research except for certain records restricted by statute or university policy. Restricted material includes personnel-related files, including search, review, promotion, and tenure files; student educational records; client/patient records; and records of executive officers of the university.
The Brace papers includes restricted material in the following categories:
Personnel Related Records -- Boxes 1 and 39
Student Academic Records -- Box 39
Charles Loring Brace IV was born in New Hampshire in 1930. As a young man he had already expressed interest in the study of human origins, reason for which he pursued an undergraduate degree in Geology at Williams College, which he obtained in 1952. The College lacked an anthropology program so Brace combined courses in geology, biology, and philosophy to fulfill his interests.
C. Loring Brace, as he is known, went on to Harvard for a Master's degree in anthropology. His studies there were interrupted when Earnest A. Hooton, his professor, passed away and Brace was drafted for military service in 1954. On his return from active duty, Brace went to Maine where he did research on physical and behavioral relations among dogs at the Jackson Memorial Laboratory. Once he returned to Harvard, a year later, he did further analysis and research on the same topic to complete what would be his thesis. He received his Master's degree in 1958 and would receive his Ph.D. in 1962 from the same institution. It was during his time in Harvard that Brace met his future wife Mary L. Crozier. "Mimi" worked at the Peabody Museum where he was also doing research. She would go on to do some research with him and illustrate his books.
During the course of his doctoral study, National Science Foundation and fellowship support allowed him to do field work in Abri Pataud, France, and research on museum collections in several European countries including Italy, Switzerland, Austria, France, Germany, and Great Britain. Brace also analyzed Neanderthal fossils in the Krapina region in former Yugoslavia. After examining remains and collections in multiple institutions in Europe, Brace spent the 1960 winter term at Oxford with the support of Nikolaas Tinbergen.
After completing his doctoral studies at Harvard under the direction of William W. Howells, Brace went on to teach at the University of Wisconsin in Milwaukee as Instructor in Anthropology in 1960. The following year he was invited to the University of California, Santa Barbara as Associate Professor of Anthropology. He taught there until 1965. Brace, during his time in Milwaukee and in Santa Barbara, was instrumental in driving the creation of anthropology departments independent from former joint Sociology and Anthropology Departments. Brace went on to teach at the University of Michigan as Associate Professor of Anthropology and Curator of Physical Anthropology at the University's Museum of Anthropology. In 1971 he obtained full professorship.
In subsequent years Brace traveled through England, the Netherlands, Italy, Israel, South Africa, East Africa, China, Japan, and Southeast Asia collecting dental and cranial measurements of populations and of hominid remains. During this time he also taught as visiting professor in institutions such as the University of Auckland, New Zealand (1973), University of Hawaii (1979), and Rollins College in Florida (1987). Brace had also done some short-term summer teaching during his time in Wisconsin and at the University of Colorado.
From early in his career Brace actively published through academic journals in anthropology and related fields, through his own books and in popular media as well. Among his well-known publications are The Stages of Human Evolution: Human and Cultural Origins, Evolution in an Anthropological View, and Race is a Four Letter Word.
Brace work is known for his claim that Neanderthals are one of four stages of human evolution and thus are ancestors to Homo Sapiens. His detailed and wide-ranging research on dentition and cranio-facial features led him to maintain that structural reduction can result from selection relaxation, also known as the Probable Mutation Effect. This was highlighted in his research on Asian populations where tooth size reduction and continuity resulted from cultural practices. His research also explored the origins of the 'race' concept, its development and application and how its use has been biologically unsupported. He suggests using the 'clines' concept and geographical names for population clusters.
In 2006 the American Association of Physical Anthropology honored Brace's achievements in the anthropological field with the Charles Darwin lifetime achievement award. His work has also been recognized by colleagues in the filed through the publication Professor C. Loring Brace: Bringing Physical Anthropology ("Kicking and Screaming" Into the 21st Century! In 2008, Brace retired from his long career at the University of Michigan.
-------------------------
Sources Consulted:
Curriculum Vitae
Falk, Dean and Noriko Seguchi, "Professor C. Loring Brace: Bringing Physical Anthropology ("Kicking and Screaming" Into the 21st Century!" in Retrospectives: Works and Lives of Michigan Anthropologists vol. 16, no. 1, Ann Arbor, MI: MPublishing, University of Michigan Library, 2006.
Ferrie, Helke. "An Interview with C. Loring Brace" in Current Anthropology, Vol. 38, No. 5 (December 1997), pp. 851-869.
The papers of anthropologist and professor C. Loring Brace document his research, publications and teaching. Material includes extensive correspondence, research material including visual material illustrating crania, bones, teeth and mandibles, also topical files and material Kennewick Man case. The papers are arranged in ten series: Biographical and Personal, Correspondence, 1966-2002, Correspondence, 1986-2009, Professional Service and Activities, Publications, Research, Teaching Materials, Topical Files, Kennewick, and Visual Materials.
Subjects:
Brace, C. Loring.; Fossil hominids.; Human evolution.; Kennewick Man.; Physical anthropology.; Prehistoric man.; Race.; University of Michigan. Department of Anthropology.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Museum of Anthropology.
- Biographical and Personal
  The Biographical and Personal series, 1969-2008 (0.75 linear feet) contains correspondence with family members, biographical material, documentation related Brace's University of Michigan appointment, sabbaticals and retirement. Also included are his curriculum vitae and several folders of limericks and poems written by him.
  - Brace, Charles Loring, 1862 (Box 1)
  - Brace Documentary, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Brace Genealogy, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Connor Bill (Re:Gerald Warner Brace), 1998 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box 1)
  - Falk and Seguchi, Biographical Article, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Gerald Brace-Incognita, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Harris Case (Box 1)
  - House (Box 1)
  - Kennewick Connections (Box 1)
  - Limericks, undated (Box 1)
  - Limericks, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1975-2001 (Box 1)
  - Poems, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - C. Loring Brace, undated (Box 1)
    - Mary L. Brace, undated (Box 1)
  - Professional Services-Royalties, 1978-2007 (Box 1)
  - Retirement, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Retirement, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Sabbatical, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Sabbatical, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Sabbatical, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Sabbatical, 2006 (Box 1)
  - UM Terms of Appointment, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Abeyta, Loring, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
    - Brace (personal correspondence), 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Brace, 1971-2004; 3 folders (Box 39)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2034 ]
    - Brace, Charles Loring V (Box 1)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2043 ]
    - Brace, Gerald, 1973-2003; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Brace, Gerald Warner and Huldah Laird, 1975-1987 (Box 1)
    - Brace, Hudson, 1988-2006 (Box 1)
    - Brace, Huldah Laird, 1975-1987 (Box 1)
    - Brace, Jerome Tiffany, 1984-2003 (Box 1)
    - Brace, Mary L., 2005-2006; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Brace, Roger and Peggy, 1985-1997 (Box 1)
    - Brace, Susanne, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Eliot, Sam, undated (Box 1)
    - Hoagland Hudson, 1969-1972 (Box 1)
    - Hoagland Hudson, 1973-1990 (Box 1)
    - Horn, William Brace, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - Gotshalk, Lincoln, 1999-2006 (Box 1)
    - Gotshalk, Ralph Walter, 2006 (Box 1)
    - Norton, Richard, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Seeley, Barbara Brace, 1973-2002 (Box 1)
    - Seeley, Ralph, 1997-2005 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1966-2002
  The Correspondence, 1966-2002 (7 linear feet) series is one of two correspondence series within the collection. These two series reflect Brace's original arrangement of his files in two distinct locations. These two series also cover different timeframes. Materials included in this particular series go back to the 1960s when Brace taught briefly at the University of California in Santa Barbara. Correspondence found here also covers his career at the University of Michigan as professor and as curator at the University's Museum of Anthropology. Correspondence related to his research travels can also be found here, as well as from his visiting professor stints at the University of Hawaii and the University of Auckland, Australia.
  Correspondence can be found here in the form of letters, printed-out electronic mail, some postcards, telegrams and other formats. Contents are arranged alphabetically and include communications with professional acquaintances, students, research institutions around the world, fellow researchers, publishers, professional organizations, and other contacts. Correspondents include: Dean Falk, Tsunehiko Hanihara, Maciej Henneberg, Ashley Montagu, Stephen Molnar, William Haviland, William Howells, Kevin Hunt, Frank Livingstone, Noriko Seguchi, Stanley Garn, Conrad Quintyn, Frank Spencer, Takery Akazawa, Phillippe Rushton, and Karen Rosenberg among others.
  - A, General, 1967-1972 (Box 1)
  - A, General, 1974-1983 (Box 1)
  - A, General, 1984-1988 (Box 1)
  - Aiello, Leslie, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Akazawa, Takeru, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Akazawa, Takeru, 1992-1995 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Richard D., 1976 (Box 1)
  - Anthropometric Equipment, 1967-1974 (Box 1)
  - Anthropometry, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - Ape Man, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Arthur, Joyce [Gish], 1997 (Box 2)
  - Athbaskan, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Australian Institute of Aboriginal Studies, 1978 (Box 2)
  - B, General, 1968-1973 (Box 2)
  - B, General, 1974-1981 (Box 2)
  - B, General, 1984-1986 (Box 2)
  - Babler, William, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Bailey, Stephen, 1976-1979 (Box 2)
  - Barondess, David, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Barnes, Gina L., 1987 (Box 2)
  - Barnett, Gary, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Behrend College, 1976-1980 (Box 2)
  - Berkeley, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Bick, Paul, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Black, Thomas K.III, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Blackinton, Paulina, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Bookstein, Fred L., 1976 (Box 2)
  - Borgognini-Tarli, Silvana, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Bowdler, Sandra, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Bowlsby, Joyce, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Brandt, Kari, 1996-1999 (Box 2)
  - Bridges, Patricia, 1982-1994 (Box 2)
  - Bromage, Timothy, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Alison, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Sheilagh T., 1984-1990 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Thomas M., 1973-1981 (Box 2)
  - Buettner-Janusch, John, 1979-1992 (Box 2)
  - Buffalo (Sutter, Richard), 1996 (Box 2)
  - Buikstra, Jane, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - C, General, 1968-1972 (Box 2)
  - C, General, 1974-1989; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Cabana, Graciela, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Calgary, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Calhoun, Terry, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Cambridge, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Carlson, Kristian, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Cartmill, Matt, 1992-1998 (Box 2)
  - Central Washington, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Chang, K.C.,1985 --, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Children's Aid, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Children's Aid Society, 1990-1997 (Box 2)
  - Choe, Ian, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Cincinnati (Society of), 1986 (Box 2)
  - Cladistics, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Geoffrey, Clark, 1992-2003 (Box 2)
  - Coleman, Loren, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Collard, Mark, 2001-2003 (Box 2)
  - Collins, John, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Comas, Juan, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Computer, 1972-1980 (Box 2)
  - Cook, Della C. (Box 2)
  - Corruccini, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Coss, Richard, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Cossman, Jeffrey, 1973-1994 (Box 2)
  - Crawford, Gary, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Crummet, Tracy, 1991 (Box 2)
  - D, 1967-1971 (Box 2)
  - D, 1974-1986 (Box 2)
  - D, 1984-1989 (Box 2)
  - Dahlberg, Albert, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Deer Isle, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Deer Isle, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Deetz, James, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Delisle, Richard, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Discover, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Donaldson, John, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Dog -- Complaints, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Dog -- Complaints, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Dowd, Maureen, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Dubois, Eugene, 1982 (Box 3)
  - E, 1968-1978 (Box 3)
  - E, 1974-1983 (Box 3)
  - E, 1984-1995 (Box 3)
  - Eckhardt, Bob, 1987-1995 (Box 3)
  - Edwards, Roberta, 1986-1996 (Box 3)
  - Egypt, 1995-1997 (Box 3)
  - Elliot, Ward, 1995-2005 (Box 3)
  - Ellzey, Tom, 1990-2004 (Box 3)
  - Ember and Ember, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Emory University, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Erickson, Paul A., 1976-1987 (Box 3)
  - Europe, 1983 (Box 3)
  - European Anthropologists Association, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Evon, Darcy, 1984 (Box 3)
  - F, 1967-1981 (Box 3)
  - F, 1974-1982 (Box 3)
  - F, 1984-1989 (Box 3)
  - Falk, Dean, 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Falk, Dean, 1978-1985 (Box 3)
  - Falk, Dean, 1989-2001 (Box 3)
  - Falk, Dean, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
  - Falk, Dean, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Feng, Jia-Jun, 1981-1985 (Box 3)
  - Fenichel, Deborah, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Ferrie, Helke, 1996-1998 (Box 3)
  - Fezer, Karl, 1987-1992 (Box 3)
  - Finney, Ben, 1967-1986 (Box 3)
  - Firmin, Antenor, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Fleagel, John, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Foley, Jim (Chris), 1995-1997 (Box 3)
  - Fox, Sherry, 2002-2004 (Box 3)
  - Frank, Reanne, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Frayer, Dave, 1974-1987 (Box 3)
  - Frayer, Dave, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Frey, Brent, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Friedlander, Jonathan, 1998 (Box 3)
  - FROM (Foundation for Research into the Origin of Man, 1979-1983 (Box 3)
  - Fullerton (California State Univesity-Bromage), 1978 (Box 3)
  - G, 1967-1973 (Box 3)
  - G, 1974-1983 (Box 3)
  - G, 1984-1986 (Box 3)
  - Garn, Stanley, 1973-2006 (Box 3)
  - Gates, Henry Louis, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Genet, Russell Merle, 1996 (Box 3)
  - George Washington University, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Gilchrist, John, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Godfrey, Laurie, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Golson, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Gordon, Mark, 1973-1990 (Box 3)
  - Gordon, Mark, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Gould, Stephen Jay, 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Graham, Janet, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Green, Roger C., 1974-1986 (Box 4)
  - Greenfield, L.O. (Box 4)
  - Griffin, James B., 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Groves, Colin, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Gruhn, Ruth, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Guan, Yueling, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Guillen, Sonia, 1979-1991 (Box 4)
  - Gunnell, Gregg, 1987 (Box 4)
  - H, 1967-1973 (Box 4)
  - H, 1974-1983 (Box 4)
  - H, 1984-1990 (Box 4)
  - Hall, Roberta L., 1975-1988 (Box 4)
  - Hamilton, Margaret, 1968-1979 (Box 4)
  - Hanihara, Tsunehiko, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Hanihara, Tsunehiko, 1981-2004 (Box 4)
  - Han, Kangxin, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Harding and Smedley, 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Harris, Edward, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Harris, Edward F., 1995 (Box 4)
  - Harris, James E., 1969 (Box 4)
  - Harvard, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Harwit, Martin, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Hasselblad Foundation, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Haviland, William, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Haviland, William, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Hawks, John, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Heathcote, Gary, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Heider, Karl, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Heim, J.L., 1992-1994 (Box 4)
  - Henneberg, Maciej, 1995-1998 (Box 4)
  - Henneberg, Maciej, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Hinton, Robert J., 1975-1983 (Box 4)
  - Hockett, Charles, 1989-1993 (Box 4)
  - Hoffman, Laurie, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Hong Huynnh, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Houle, Brian, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Howell, F. Clark, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Howells, William, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Howells, William, 1967-1995 (Box 4)
  - Howes, Dustin E., 1994 (Box 4)
  - Hughes, Ed, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Hulse, Frederick, 1986-1989 (Box 4)
  - Human Biology Council, 1969-1992 (Box 4)
  - Hunley, Keith, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Hunt, Kevin, 1984-2000; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Hunt, Kevin, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Hunter College, 1995 (Box 4)
  - I, 1967-1982 (Box 4)
  - I, 1984-1994 (Box 4)
  - Ikawa-Smith, Fumiko, 1984-1996 (Box 4)
  - Ikeda, Jiro, 1981-1984 (Box 4)
  - Ingersoll, Dan, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Isis, 2003 (Box 4)
  - J, 1968-1981 (Box 4)
  - J, 1974-1983 (Box 4)
  - J, 1984-1995 (Box 4)
  - Jablonski, Nina, 1983-2001 (Box 4)
  - Jacobs, Kenneth, 1973-1988 (Box 4)
  - Jenner, Jonathan, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Jolly, Cliff, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Doug Jones, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Jungers, Bill, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - K, 1967-1994 (Box 5)
  - K, 1974-1983 (Box 5)
  - K, 1984-1989 (Box 5)
  - Kandula, Sushma, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Kaplan, Richard, 1985-2005 (Box 5)
  - Kennedy, Kenneth A. R., 1997 (Box 5)
  - Kilmer, Mark E., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Kimbel and Martin, 1993 (Box 5)
  - King Jr., Martin Luther, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Koritzer, Richard T., 1978 (Box 5)
  - Kowalesky, Richard, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Kramer, Andrew, 1987-1996 (Box 5)
  - Kuhl, Stefan, 1994 (Box 5)
  - L, 1969-1981 (Box 5)
  - L, 1974-1984 (Box 5)
  - L, 1984-1991 (Box 5)
  - Larsen, Clark, 1979-1988 (Box 5)
  - Lauer, Carol, 1973-1986 (Box 5)
  - LaVelle, Marquisa, 1976-1989 (Box 5)
  - LeBlanc, Steven, 1995-2002 (Box 5)
  - Lee, Jean Y., 1995-2002 (Box 5)
  - Lee, Yun Kuen, 1994-1996 (Box 5)
  - Leftkowitz, Mary, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Lenkeit, Roberta, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Leonard, Michael N., 1995-2006 (Box 5)
  - Leonard, William, 1984-1992 (Box 5)
  - Li Young-Yi, 1985-2005 (Box 5)
  - Li, Zhikun, 1984-1986 (Box 5)
  - Lieberman, Len, 1988-2007 (Box 5)
  - Lindgran, Charlotte, 1994-1998 (Box 5)
  - Lingua Franca, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Livingstone, Frank, 1995-2005 (Box 5)
  - London, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Loth, Susan, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Lukacs, John, 1981-1994 (Box 5)
  - Lukacs and Walimbe, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Lux Marcia, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Lyons, Andrew, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - M, 1968-1973 (Box 5)
  - M, 1974-1983 (Box 5)
  - M, 1984-1991 (Box 5)
  - Maba, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Madison, Wisconsin, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Mahler, Paul, 1973-1979 (Box 5)
  - Marks, Jonathan, 1988-1995 (Box 5)
  - Martin Luther King Day, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Massey, Vincent, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Mayr, Ernst, 1986-1998 (Box 5)
  - Melbye, Jerry, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Michigan Archaeological Society, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project, 1968-1970 (Box 5)
  - Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project, 1971-1979 (Box 5)
  - Miller, Jeff, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Milotich, Mark, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Miranda, Maria Teresa, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Milosz, John Peter, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Mirazon Lahr, Marta, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966-1967 (Box 5)
  - Molnar, Stephen, 1967-1973 (Box 5)
  - Molnar, Stephen, 1974-2003 (Box 6)
  - Molnar, Stephen (prism-Prints), undated (Box 6)
  - Montagu, Ashley, 1971-1975 (Box 6)
  - Montagu, Ashley, 1975-1996 (Box 6)
  - Montagu, Ashley, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Montagu, Ashley, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Moore, Lorna G., 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Moore, John H., 1996-1998 (Box 6)
  - Moore, Megan, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Moses, Yolanda, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Murayama, Sichiro, 1990-1993 (Box 6)
  - N, 1967-1971 (Box 6)
  - N, 1974-1983 (Box 6)
  - N, 1984-1992 (Box 6)
  - Nagai, Masafumi, 1981-1984 (Box 6)
  - Nelson, Russell, 1983-1991 (Box 6)
  - Nelson, Russell, 1991-2002 (Box 6)
  - Nelson, Russell, 1995-2002 (Box 6)
  - Nelson, Russell-thesis, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Nishimura, Masao, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Niskanen, Markku, 1995-1997 (Box 6)
  - O, 1967-1981 (Box 6)
  - O, 1974-1982 (Box 6)
  - O, 1984-1990 (Box 6)
  - Oberlin, 2002-2004 (Box 6)
  - O'Brien, Kevin L., 1995-1997 (Box 6)
  - O'Connell, Barbara, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Olatunde, Sumaiya, 2002-2003 (Box 6)
  - O'Shea, John, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Oxnard, Charles, 1982 (Box 6)
  - P, 1967-1981 (Box 6)
  - P, 1974-1983 (Box 6)
  - P, 1984-1996 (Box 6)
  - PALANTH, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Paleoanthropology Society, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Pan, Qifeng, 1987-1992 (Box 6)
  - Peters, Nancy, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Pietrusewsky, Michael, 1984-1996 (Box 6)
  - Poirier, Frank, 1977-1998 (Box 6)
  - Geoffrey Pope, undated (Box 6)
  - Pritchard, P.C.H., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Proctor, Robert, 2003 (Box 6)
  - Purcell, Carl, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Q, 1969-1975 (Box 6)
  - Quintyn, Conrad, 1993-1999 (Box 6)
  - Quintyn, Conrad, 1999-2005 (Box 6)
  - R, 1967-1982 (Box 6)
  - R, 1974-1982 (Box 6)
  - R, 1984-1991 (Box 6)
  - Race, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Rackham Predoctoral Fellowship Committee, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Raspe, Pamela, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Reynolds, Monica, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Relethford, John, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Rightmire, Philip, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Robb, John, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Robertson, Jennifer, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Robertson, Marcia, undated (Box 6)
  - Rochester, 1992-1993 (Box 6)
  - Rochester (Eastman Dental Center), 1991 (Box 6)
  - Rollins College (Lauer), 1986-1987 (Box 6)
  - Rosen, Richard, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Rosenberg, Karen, 1981-2004 (Box 6)
  - Rosenberg, Karen (prelims), 1981 (Box 6)
  - Rudman, Steve, 1984-1995 (Box 6)
  - Rushton, J. Philippe, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Rushton, J. Philippe, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Russell, Mary, 1981-1986 (Box 7)
  - Ryan, Alan S., 1977-1989; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - S, 1967-1981 (Box 7)
  - S, 1974-1983 (Box 7)
  - S, 1984-1987 (Box 7)
  - Safire, William, 1982-2003 (Box 7)
  - Safire, William, 1995-2003 (Box 7)
  - Salzano, Francisco M., 2002 (Box 7)
  - Sandt, Sam, 1976-1978 (Box 7)
  - Santa Barbara, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Sasaki, Ken-ichi, 1985-1996 (Box 7)
  - Schenkman, Alfred, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Schepartz, Lynne, 1983 (Box 7)
  - Schmalz, Robert, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Schoeninger, Margaret, 1978-1989 (Box 7)
  - Schofield, Edmund, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Scott, Eugenie, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Scott, G. Richard, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Scott, J. Paul, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Seguchi, Noriko, 1989-1999 (Box 7)
  - Seguchi, Noriko, 2000-2004 (Box 7)
  - Shao, Xiang-Qing, 1981-1990 (Box 7)
  - Shanklin, Eugenia, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Shipman, Pat, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
  - Shipman, Pat, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Siegel, Michael, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Siegel, Nicole, 2005-2006 (Box 7)
  - Silverberg, Jim, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Simons, Elwyn, L., 1961-1984 (Box 7)
  - Singh, Mohinder Pal, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Skinner, Mark, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Smart, Tristine, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Fred, 1976-1983 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Fred, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Gerry, 2009 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Holly, 1979-1989 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Shelley and Francis Harold, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Shelley, 1989-1996 (Box 7)
  - Smithsonian, 1983 (Box 7)
  - Social Biology, 1970-1985 (Box 7)
  - Solheim, Wilhelm,., 1986-1988 (Box 7)
  - Solheim (Conference), 1988 (Box 7)
  - Sohn-Yoon, Songy, 1986-1991 (Box 7)
  - Spencer, Frank, 1981-1997 (Box 7)
  - Springfield, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Spuhler, James, 1982-1992 (Box 7)
  - Stanford, 1988-1995 (Box 7)
  - Stanford Center, 1976-1979 (Box 7)
  - Statistics Bookstein, undated (Box 7)
  - Steegman, Ted, 1995-1999 (Box 7)
  - Stein, Tamara, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Stephan, Carl, 2002-2003 (Box 7)